Theo Lincke

SUMMARY CONTACT

I am an Applied Math and Computer Science major with 3+ years experience in network programming and flight control software with an interest in software simulation for nonlinear dynamics and chaos theory.

I am looking for a software engineering or applied mathematics internship or research position for the summer 2021 term.

P: 303 478 1391

E: thli2739@colorado.edu

A: 2361 Braun Dr Golden CO 80401

Portfolio: https://tlincke125.github.io

EDUCATION

University of Colorado, Boulder Boulder, Colorado 2018-2022

BS Computer Science BS Applied Mathematics

Current GPA: 3.905

SKILLS

Languages:

C, C++, Python, Matlab, Bash, Java

Linux:

Arch, Gentoo, Ubuntu LFS

Frameworks:

ROS/ROS2, ZeroMQ, Sockets

Electrical Engineering:

Arduino, Platformio, U-Boot

Mathematical Methods:

Nonlinear ODE / PDE Simulation

PERSONAL PROJECTS

ODE Solver in python with adaptive time step and vectorized inputs

Linear Algebra and Neural Network
Library from the ground up in C++

Virtual Any Dimensional Rubik's Cube Solver in Java

SVD Facial Detection System in MATLAB

Multi Platform / Language Message passing framework with a ZeroMQ backend

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Rincon Research Inc

Software Engineer Intern June 15 2020 - August 8 2020

- → Worked on a team of electrical engineers to design a GUI based software defined radio simulator.
- → I designed an advanced backend asynchronous networking system to pass upwards of 9 million data points per second

Kelvin Inc

Software / Embedded Engineer Intern *May* 15 2019 - August 28 2019

- → Worked during the forefront of a real time initiative.
- → Provided case studies on RTEMS, FreeRTOS and PREEMPT_RT linux kernel patch on x86 and arm architectures.

CU Boulder Robotic Mining

Lead Embedded Software Engineer August 2018 - Present → Innovated application based modular robotic framework using ZeroMQ sockets and a dedicated serialization library.

Colorado Taekwondo Institute

Martial Arts Instructor / Trainer
July 2014 - August 2017

→ After receiving my junior (2014) black belt, I trained in leadership and communication classes for two years before taking on my first class working with 5-9 year old beginners.